[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "‘He prayeth best, who loveth best’.- Who said it?",
    "options": ["John Milton", "John Donne", "Lord Byron", "S. T. Coleridge"],
    "answer": "S. T. Coleridge"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "The controlling sentence of a paragraph in known as-",
    "options": [
      "content modulator",
      "terminator",
      "thesis statement",
      "topic sentence"
    ],
    "answer": "topic sentence"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Choose the correct comparative form of the sentence: ‘Very few boys are as industrious as Zaman’.",
    "options": [
      "Zaman is one of the most industrious boys.",
      "Zaman is more industrious than most other boys.",
      "Zaman is really industrious like other boys.",
      "Zaman is as industrious as other boys."
    ],
    "answer": "Zaman is more industrious than most other boys."
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "Identify the appropriate preposition: Your opinion is identical __ mine.",
    "options": ["for", "in", "with", "by"],
    "answer": "with"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "‘Paradise Lost’ attempted to-",
    "options": [
      "justify the ways of man to God.",
      "show that Satan and God have equal power",
      "justify the ways of God to man",
      "explain why both good and evil are necessary."
    ],
    "answer": "justify the ways of God to man"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "The synonym for ‘panoramic’ is-",
    "options": ["scenic", "narrow", "limited", "restricted"],
    "answer": "scenic"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "The antonym for ‘slothful’ is-",
    "options": ["playful", "sluggish", "energetic", "quarrelsome"],
    "answer": "energetic"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Alexander Pope’s ‘Essay on Man’ is a-",
    "options": ["novel", "treatise", "short story", "poem"],
    "answer": "poem"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "‘By and large’ means-",
    "options": ["everywhere", "very large", "mostly", "far away"],
    "answer": "mostly"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Francis Bacon is an illustrious _",
    "options": ["essayist", "dramatist", "novelist", "journalist"],
    "answer": "essayist"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "‘He could not win but learnt a lot.’ Which part of speech is the word ‘but’?",
    "options": ["an adverb", "a verb", "an adjective", "a conjunction"],
    "answer": "a conjunction"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "Select the appropriate preposition: ‘Are you doing’ anything special --- the weekend?’",
    "options": ["at", "with", "on", "for"],
    "answer": "at"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "What is the plural form of ‘sheep’?",
    "options": ["sheeps", "sheep", "sheepes", "sheepses"],
    "answer": "sheep"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "‘Sweet are the uses of adversity’ is quoted from Shakespeare’s-",
    "options": [
      "Julius Caesar",
      "Macbeth",
      "Comedy of Errors",
      "As you Like It"
    ],
    "answer": "As you Like It"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "What is the verb form of the word ‘ability’?",
    "options": ["capable", "inability", "enable", "unable"],
    "answer": "enable"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "The word ‘equivocation’ refers to -",
    "options": [
      "stating like an author",
      "two contradictory things in the same statement",
      "free expression of opinions",
      "a true statement"
    ],
    "answer": "two contradictory things in the same statement"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "“Life’s but a walking shadow, a poor player, That struts and frets his hour upon the stage, And then is heard no more;” These memorable lines in Shakespearean tragedy are spoken by-",
    "options": ["Lady Macbeth", "Banquo", "Duncan", "Macbeth"],
    "answer": "Macbeth"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "Which of the following words is spelt correctly?",
    "options": [
      "authoratative",
      "autheritative",
      "authoritative",
      "authoratative"
    ],
    "answer": "authoritative"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "Find out the active form of the sentence: ‘By whom can our country be saved?’",
    "options": [
      "Who can save our country?",
      "Our country has been saved by who?",
      "Who save our country?",
      "Who will save our country?"
    ],
    "answer": "Who can save our country?"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "“All changed, changed utterly: A terrible beauty is born.” This extract is taken from W. B. Yeats’ poem titled-",
    "options": [
      "No Second Troy",
      "Easter 1916",
      "The Second Coming",
      "The Wild Swans at Coole"
    ],
    "answer": "Easter 1916"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "Identify the correct passive form: ‘Do not close the door.’",
    "options": [
      "Let not the door close",
      "Let not the door be closed",
      "Let not the door close",
      "Let not door closed"
    ],
    "answer": "Let not the door be closed"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "The poetic drama ‘Murder in the Cathedral’ was written by -",
    "options": ["Harold Pinter", "G. B. Shaw", "T. S. Eliot", "Samuel Backett"],
    "answer": "T. S. Eliot"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "‘All for love’ is a drama written by-",
    "options": [
      "John Dryden",
      "William Congreve",
      "John Bunyan",
      "Francis Bacon"
    ],
    "answer": "John Dryden"
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "Sitting happily, the chicken laid eggs. The underlined part is a/an-",
    "options": [
      "noun clause",
      "subordinate clause",
      "independent clause",
      "coordinate clause"
    ],
    "answer": "subordinate clause"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "Caliban is an important character from Shakespeare’s-",
    "options": ["The Tempest", "Hamlet", "Macbeth", "Othello"],
    "answer": "The Tempest"
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "What kind of noun is ‘river’?",
    "options": ["Material", "Collective", "Proper", "Common"],
    "answer": "Common"
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "‘Oh, lift me as a wave, a leaf, a cloud! I fall upon the thorns of life! I bleed!’ The extract is taken from P. B. Shelley’s poem-",
    "options": ["The Cloud", "To a Skylark", "Ode to the West Wind", "Adonais"],
    "answer": "Ode to the West Wind"
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "Who wrote the short story ‘The Ant and the Grasshopper’?",
    "options": [
      "Guy de maupassant",
      "W. Somerset Maugham",
      "J. K. Rawlings",
      "O’Henry"
    ],
    "answer": "W. Somerset Maugham"
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "The word ‘vital’ is a/an-",
    "options": ["noun", "adverb", "adjective", "verb"],
    "answer": "adjective"
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "‘To get along with’ means-",
    "options": ["to adjust", "to interest", "to accompany", "to walk"],
    "answer": "to adjust"
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "question": "‘Caesar and Cleopatra’ is-",
    "options": [
      "a tragedy by William Shakespeare",
      "a poem by Lord Byron",
      "a play by Bernard Shaw",
      "a novel by S. T. Coleridge"
    ],
    "answer": "a play by Bernard Shaw"
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "question": "Identify the right tense: ‘My father __ before I came’.",
    "options": [
      "would be leaving",
      "had been leaving",
      "had left",
      "will leave"
    ],
    "answer": "had left"
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "question": "Which of the following words is spelt incorrectly?",
    "options": ["reminescence", "glycerin", "idiosyncrasy", "lexicography"],
    "answer": "reminescence"
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "question": "Who wrote the picaresque novel titled ‘Tom Jones’?",
    "options": [
      "Samuel Richardson",
      "Horace Walpole",
      "Henry Fielding",
      "Laurence Sterne"
    ],
    "answer": "Henry Fielding"
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "question": "The story of ‘Moby Dick’ centers on--",
    "options": ["a mermaid", "a whale", "a crocodile", "a shark"],
    "answer": "a whale"
  }
]
